出    演
格里高利
派   克
奥黛丽
赫 本
谨介绍
威廉 维勒
作    品
罗马
假日
约翰 戴夫顿
原    著
道尔顿 特兰波
编    剧
伊恩 麦克莱伦 亨特尔
本    片
拍摄及录音
均在意大利
罗马完成
摄 影 导 演
弗兰克                                                                         亨瑞
F.潘勒 A.S.C.                                                阿勒坎
艺 术 导 演
哈尔                                                                          沃特尔
佩雷拉                                                    泰勒
剪    辑
罗伯特 斯文克 A.C.E
冲印于 CINECITTA工作室-罗马，意大利
联 合 制 片 人
罗伯特  维勒
配    乐
乔吉斯  奥瑞克
制片 兼 导演
威廉  维勒
派拉蒙新闻
新闻速递
派拉蒙新闻为您带来安公主出访伦敦的专题报道
Paramount News brings you a special coverage of Princess Ann's visit to London,
这是她在欧洲各国首都进行友好宣传的第一站
the first stop on her much-publicized goodwill tour of European capitals.
她受到英国皇室级别的隆重欢迎
She gets a royal welcome from the British,
这位欧洲最古老皇族之一的高贵年轻成员受到数千民众的热烈欢呼
as thousands cheer the gracious young member of one of Europe's oldest ruling families.
在为期3天的宣传活动结束后 她参观了白金汉宫
After three days of continuous activity and a visit to Buckingham Palace,
安飞抵阿姆斯特丹
Ann flew to Amsterdam,
在那里 公主殿下为新的国际援助大厦奠基
where Her Royal Highness dedicated the new International Aid Building
并出席了一艘邮轮的命名仪式
and christened an ocean liner,
之后前往巴黎
then went to Paris,
出席多项官方活动
where she attended many official functions
旨在加强同西欧各国的贸易关系
designed to cement trade relations between her country and the Western European nations.
现在终于 来到了不朽之城 罗马
And so, to Rome, the Eternal City,
为迎接公主的到来 罗马举行了盛大的阅兵式
where the princess' visit was marked by a spectacular military parade
突击步兵团乐队的演奏将阅兵式推向了高潮
highlighted by the band of the crack Bersaglieri regiment.
从年轻的公主的微笑中你丝毫看不出持续一周公共场合露面的疲惫感
The smiling young princess showed no sign of the strain of the week's continuous public appearances,
当晚 在该国大使馆
and, at her country's embassy that evening,
该国驻意大利大使为她特设晚宴并举行了舞会
a formal reception and ball in her honor was given by her country's ambassador to Italy.
公主殿下
Her Royal Highness.
罗马教廷大使 奥托蒙特阁下
His Excellency, the Papal Nuncio, Monsignor Altomonte.
雨果 梅西 德 法明顿爵士
Sir Hugo Macy de Farmington.
- 晚上好 雨果爵士
- 晚上好 公主殿下
- Good evening, Sir Hugo.
- Good evening, Your Royal Highness.
克汉尼普王储殿下
His Highness the Maharajah of Khanipur
及拉杰库玛尼王妃
and the Rajkumari.
我非常荣幸您们能出席
I'm so glad that you could come.
- 谢谢
- 谢谢 殿下
- Thank you.
- Thank you, madam.
艾瑞克 af 玛欣斯贾纳 卑尔根斯基欧德男爵
Friherre Erick af Massinsjarna Bergenskiold.
伊斯特万 保卢西 纳基瓦洛斯王子
Prince Istvan Barlossy Nagyavaros.
您好
How do you do?
公主殿下 这是卢茨腾斯臣奥兹王子及王妃
Lhre Hoheit der Furst und die Fursten von und zu Luchtenstichenholz.
哈瑞 辛格爵士及卡马克 辛格夫人
Sir Hari Singh and Kmark Singh.
冯 马斯特兰德伯爵及伯爵夫人
The Count and Countess Von Marstrand.
晚上好 伯爵夫人
Good evening, Countess.
晚上好
Good evening.
诺 德 卡莫斯爵士及夫人
Señor e Señora Joao de Camoes.
晚上好
Good evening.
哈桑 EL 丁 帕夏
Hassan El Din Pasha.
您好
How do you do?
我不喜欢这件睡袍
I hate this nightgown.
我不喜欢我所有的睡袍 还有 我也不喜欢我所有的内衣
I hate all my nightgowns, and I hate all my underwear, too.
亲爱的 你的东西都很漂亮
My dear, you have lovely things.
可我还没有200岁那么老
But I'm not two hundred years old.
为什么我就不能穿着睡衣睡觉？
Why can't I sleep in pajamas?
睡衣！
Pajamas!
只要上衣
Just the top part.
你知道吗 有些人睡觉的时候几乎什么都不穿？
Did you know there are people who sleep with absolutely nothing on at all?
我得很高兴的说我不知道有这种事
I rejoice to say that I did not.
听啊
Listen.
安 你的拖鞋
Ann, your slippers.
请穿上您的拖鞋 离开窗户那里
Please put on your slippers and come away from the window.
您的牛奶还有饼干
Your milk and crackers.
我们所做的每件事都是为了您好
Everything we do is so wholesome.
这能帮助你入睡的
They'll help you to sleep.
我太累了 睡不着 连眼睛都闭不上
I'm too tired to sleep. I shan't sleep a wink.
噢 亲爱的 要是你不介意的话 明天的行程表 或者说“时间表”
Now, my dear, if you don't mind, tomorrow's schedule, or "schedule,"
随便你喜欢吧 反正都是一样的
whichever you prefer. Both are correct.
8:30 同大使馆工作人员在这里用早餐
8:30, breakfast here with the embassy staff.
9:00 我们出发去波林纳里汽车厂
9:00, we leave for the Polinari automotive works,
他们将把一辆小轿车作为礼物赠送给您
where you'll be presented with a small car.
谢谢
Thank you.
但您不能接受
Which you will not accept.
我不能收 谢谢
No, thank you.
10:35 视察食品与农业机构
10:35, inspection of food and agricultural organization,
他们会赠给您一颗橄榄树
will present you with an olive tree.
我不能收 谢谢
No, thank you.
这个您要收下
Which you will accept.
谢谢
Thank you.
10:55 新建的孤儿院
10:55, the New Foundling Home for Orphans.
你要出席放置奠基石的仪式
You will preside over the laying of the cornerstone.
讲话的内容同上周一是一样的
Same speech as last Monday.
贸易关系
Trade relations.
是的
Yes.
在孤儿院说这个吗？
For the orphans?
不 不 不对 是另一个讲话
No, no, no, the other one.
年轻与发展
Youth and progress.
就是这个
Precisely.
11:45 回到这里休息 不 不对
11:45, back here to rest. No, that's wrong.
11:45 回这里召开记者招待会
11:45, conference here with the press.
甜美与庄重
Sweetness and decency.
1:00 同外交部用午餐
1:00 sharp, lunch with the Foreign Ministry.
你要系上白色的花边并配上一束
You will wear your white lace and carry a bouquet of
- 非常小的粉玫瑰
- very small pink roses.
- Very small pink roses.
3:05 匾额赠送仪式
3:05, presentation of a plaque.
谢谢
Thank you.
4:10 检阅宪兵特勤卫队...
4:10, review Special Guard of Carabinieri...
我不能收 谢谢
No, thank you.
- 4:45 回到这里换...
- 您好 真迷人
- 4:45, back here to change...
- How do you do? Charmed.
- ...上您的制服会见...
- 很高兴...
- ...into your uniform to meet the...
- So happy...
别说了！
Stop!
- 我的上帝啊！
- 别说了！别说了！别说了！
- Good heavens!
- Stop! Stop! Stop!
没事 亲爱的 没洒出来
It's all right, dear. It didn't spill.
我才不在乎它洒没洒
I don't care if it spilled or not.
就算我淹死在里边我也不在乎！
I don't care if I drowned in it!
亲爱的 你病了
My dear, you're ill.
我派人去把博纳科温医生请来
I'll send for Dr. Bonnachoven.
我不要博纳科温医生！就让我安静的死掉吧
I don't want Dr. Bonnachoven! Please let me die in peace.
你不会死的
You're not dying.
别管我！
Leave me!
- 别管我！
- 你就是有些紧张了 控制你的情绪 安
- Leave me!
- It's nerves. Control yourself, Ann.
我不要！
I don't want to!
公主殿下！
Your Highness!
我去把博纳科温医生找来
I'll get Dr. Bonnachoven.
这没用的
It's no use.
在他赶到这里前我就会死掉
I'll be dead before he gets here.
她已经睡着了
She's asleep.
3分钟前她还是歇斯底里的 医生
She was in hysterics three minutes ago, Doctor.
您睡着了吗 殿下？
Are you asleep, ma'am?
没有！
No!
我只打扰您一小会儿 公主殿下
I'll only disturb Your Royal Highness a moment.
我真的很惭愧 博纳科温医生
I'm very ashamed, Dr. Bonnachoven.
突然间 我就哭起来了
Sudenly, I was crying.
哭 是再平常不过的事了
To cry, a perfectly normal thing to do.
最重要的是让她在出席记者招待会的时候能够冷静 放松 医生
It's most important she be calm and relaxed for the press conference, Doctor.
别担心 医生
Don't worry, Doctor.
我会冷静 放松的
I'll be calm and relaxed.
我会欠身 微笑的
I'll bow, and I'll smile.
我会改善贸易关系 还有...
I'll improve trade relations, and...
她又这样了 给她点儿什么药 医生 快点
There she goes again. Give her something, Doctor, please.
请把她的衣袖卷起来
[请注意将军的表演]
Uncover her arm, please.
那是什么？
What's that?
镇定促睡眠的药
Sleep and calm.
这会让公主殿下您感到放松并感到些许愉快的
This will relax you and make Your Highness feel a little happy.
这是一种新药 没有任何副作用
It's a new drug, quite harmless.
好了
There.
我没感觉有什么不同
I don't feel any different.
你会的 要过一阵才会起效
You will. It may take a little time to take hold.
现在 快躺下吧
Just, now, lie back.
能给我留一盏灯别关 好吗？
Can I keep just one light on?
当然可以
Of course.
我最懂得的就是遵照您的心意了
Best thing I know is to do exactly what you wish for a while.
谢谢您 医生
Thank you, Doctor.
噢 将军他！医生 快来！
Oh, The General! Doctor, quick!
我已经完全没事了
I'm perfectly all right.
晚安 殿下
Good night, ma'am.
- 晚安 殿下
- 晚安 医生
- Good night, ma'am.
- Good night, Doctor.
我赌500
[天 500里拉？你干嘛不用手纸去赌？]
Bet 500.
500 要几张？
500. How many?
1张
One.
我也要1张
I'll take one.
3张
Three.
4张
Foolish boy.
给老爹我来两张
Two for papa.
再赌500
500 more.
牌都不用看
Without looking.
500 你要跟我就得出1,000
500, and I'll raise you 1,000.
两对
Two pairs.
我拿的是三张7
I got three shy little sevens.
三条 你们可以光屁股回家了 傻瓜们
A nervous straight. Come home, you fools.
看呐 6,500里拉
Look at that. 6,500.
还不坏 这都10美元了
Not bad. That's 10 bucks.
再来一把
One more round,
我要把你们赢个干净
and I'm going to throw you gents right out in the snow.
什么 干嘛这么说？
Say, what is this?
我还要早起呢
I got to get up early.
我约了公主殿下
Date with Her Royal Highness,
她会做出优雅的姿势给我照的
who will graciously pose for some pictures.
你说什么 早起？我收到的邀请函上写的是11:45
What do you mean, early? My personal invitation says 11:45.
你赢了就不想玩了吗？
Couldn't be anything to do with the fact that you're ahead?
应该是吧
It could.
我输惨了 这是我最后5,000里拉了
It works out fine for me. This is my last 5,000,
你们这些土狼别想得到它 多谢了 艾文
and you hyenas are not gonna get it. Thanks a lot, Irving.
好的 明天早上安妮的小聚会再见
Yeah, see you at Annie's little party in the morning.
- 再见 乔
- 好的 再见
- Ciao, Joe.
- Yeah, ciao.
晚安 乔
Good night, Joe.
好了 再来一把七张牌
All right, a little seven-card stud.
算我一个
Okay with me.
真开心
So happy.
今晚你怎么样？
How are you this evening?
嘿 嘿 嘿
Hey, hey, hey.
嘿 醒醒
Hey, wake up.
非常感谢 很高兴认识你
Thank you very much. Delighted.
醒醒
Wake up.
我不能收 谢谢
No, thank you.
真迷人
Charmed.
你也很迷人
Charmed, too.
你可以坐下了
You may sit down.
我想你最好坐起来
I think you'd better sit up.
你这年纪也小得连警察都不会收容你
You're much too young to get picked up by the police.
- 警察？
- 没错 警察
- Police?
- Yep. Police.
2:15回来换衣服 2:45...
2:15 and back here to change. 2:45...
要知道 酒量不行的人就不该喝酒
You know, people who can't handle liquor shouldn't drink it.
“若是我死去 眠于地下 但只要听见你的声音”
"If I were dead and buried and I heard your voice
“即便在青草之下 我那已化为泥土的心也会欣慰的”
"beneath the sod my heart of dust would still rejoice."
你知道这首诗吗？
Do you know that poem?
那你知道什么？
What do you know?
你读书又多 穿得也好
You're well-read, well-dressed,
却在大街上打瞌睡
snoozing away in a public street.
你不介意做个解释吧？
Would you care to make a statement?
这个世界需要的是让甜美和庄重重新回归到
What the world needs is a return to sweetness and decency
青年人的灵魂里...
in the souls of its young men and...
是的 我绝对同意你的说法 不过...
Yeah, I couldn't agree with you more, but...
喝点咖啡吧 这样你就会好多了
Get yourself some coffee. You'll be all right.
听着 这辆出租车你坐吧
Look, you take the cab.
快点 上车去 回家
Come on, climb in the cab and go home.
- 真开心
- 你有带钱吗？
- So happy.
- You got any money?
我从不带钱
Never carry money.
这真不是个好习惯
That's a bad habit.
好吧 我送你 走吧
All right. I'll drop you off. Come on.
这是辆出租车！
It's a taxi!
噢 这可不是超级酋长[1935-1974 洛杉矶-芝加哥特快列车]
Well, it's not the Super Chief.
你们要到哪儿？
Where are we going?
你住哪儿？
Where do you live?
圆形竞技场
Colosseum.
噢 得了 你还没那么醉呢
Now, come on. You're not that drunk.
你真是聪明 我一点儿都没醉
You're so smart. I'm not drunk at all.
我只是非常开心罢了
I'm just being very happy.
现在 坐好 别又睡着了 来吧
There, now, don't go to sleep again. Come on.
我们要去哪儿？
Where are we going?
- 好吧
- 听着 好了 你想去什么地方？
- Okay.
- Look, now, where do you want to go?
我该把你送哪儿去？
Where shall I take you?
你住哪里？
Where do you live?
快说 快说 你住哪里？
Come on. Come on. Where do you live?
快说吧！你住哪儿？
Come on! Where do you live?
圆形竞技场
Colosseum.
她住在圆形竞技场
She lives in the Colosseum.
这地址不对
Is wrong adress.
好了 听着 小姐 对我来说 现在已经非常晚了
Now, look, signore, for me, it is very late night.
我有妻子 我还有3个小孩儿 3个小孩儿
Wife. I have three bambino, three bambino.
你知道小孩儿吗？
You know bambino?
我的出租车要收工了 我也要回家了 我要开车回家了
My taxi go home. I go home, too. Together.
玛古塔大道51号
Via Margutta 51.
玛古塔大道51号到了
Here is Via Margutta 51.
我太开心了
I am very happy.
1,000里拉
1,000 lira.
1 2 3 4千
One, two, three, four mille.
好了
Okay.
给我的？
For me?
好的 好的 现在 听我说
Okay, okay. Now, look.
- 拿上这些钱...
- 嗯？
- Take a little bit of that...
- Yeah?
她想去哪儿就把她送到什么地方去
Take her wherever she wants to go.
晚安
Good night.
噢 不行 不行 等等 等等
Oh, No, no, moument, moument.
- 不行 不行 不行 不行
- 好吧 听着
- No, no, no, no.
- All right, look.
你看 等她醒了
As soon as she wakes up, see,
她就会告诉你她要去什么地方 对吧？
she'll tell you where she wants to go, okay?
等等 等等 我的出租车可不是让人睡觉的
Moument, moument. My taxi is not for sleep.
我的出租车 不是睡觉用的 明白吗？你明白吗？
My taxi. No sleep. Understand? You understand?
听着 朋友 这不关我的事 明白吗？
Look, pal. This is not my problem, see?
我之前从没见过她 好吗
I never see her before. Okay.
这不关你的事 也不关我的事
Is not your problem. Is not my problem.
你想怎样？你不想要女孩儿 对吧？[意式英语 凑合翻译]
What you want? You don't want girl, yeah?
我不想要女孩儿
Me don't want girl.
警察！也许她会想要女孩儿
Police! Maybe she want girl.
好吧 好吧 好吧
Okay, okay, okay.
真开心...真开心...
So happy... So happy...
我该去做下头部检查了
I ought to have my head examined.
这是电梯吗？
Is this the elevator?
这是我的房间
It's my room.
非常抱歉我这样说起它 不过我晕得越来越厉害了
I'm terribly sorry to mention it, but the dizziness is getting worse.
我可以睡在这里吗？
Can I sleep here?
那是当然的
That's the general idea.
能给我件缀着玫瑰花的丝绸睡袍吗？
Can I have a silk nightgown with rosebuds on it?
我恐怕你今晚要将就一下了 穿上这些吧
I'm afraid you'll have to rough it tonight, in these.
睡衣！
Pajamas!
抱歉 亲爱的 可我不穿睡袍已经好多年了
Sorry, honey, but I haven't worn a nightgown in years.
你能替我宽衣吗 谢谢？
Will you help me get undressed, please?
好吧
Okay.
给你 剩下的你自己来吧
There you are. You can handle the rest.
我可以喝点儿吗？
May I have some?
不行
No.
好了 听着...
Now, look...
这很不寻常
This is very unusual.
我之前从未同一个男人独处过
I've never been alone with a man before,
即便是穿着衣服
even with my dress on.
现在连衣服都没穿 这太不寻常了
With my dress off, it's most unusual.
我不会介意的
I don't seem to mind.
你呢？
Do you?
我想我要出去喝杯咖啡
I think I'll go out for a cup of coffee.
你还是快点儿睡觉吧
You'd better get to sleep.
不 睡这上边
No. On this one.
真是太体贴了
So terribly nice.
听着
Here.
这些是睡衣 穿上它们睡觉
These are pajamas. They're to sleep in.
你要爬进睡衣里去 明白吗？
You're to climb into them. You understand?
谢谢
Thank you.
你要睡在躺椅上 明白吗 不是床上
And you do your sleeping on the couch, see, not on the bed.
不是椅子上 是躺椅上 听明白了吗？
Not on the chair, on the couch. Is that clear?
你知道我最喜欢的那首诗吗？
Do you know my favorite poem?
你已经念给我听过了
You've already recited that for me.
“阿瑞图萨从她在阿克落瑟劳伦山脉上的白雪沙发上醒来”[沙发同躺椅为同一词]
[阿瑞图萨在神话中变为泉水 阿瑞图萨 珀西 比希 雪莱作于1820年]
"Arethusa arose From her couch of snows In the Acroceraunian mountains."
[ARETHUSA by Percy Bysshe Shelley 1820]
- 基茨[John Keats 1795-1821 英国浪漫诗人]
- 雪莱[Percy Bysshe Shelley 1792-1822 英国抒情诗人]
- Keats.
- Shelley.
别想什么诗了 穿上睡衣吧
You just keep your mind off the poetry and on the pajamas.
一切都会好起来的 明白吗？
Everything'll be all right, see?
- 是基茨的
- 好了 我...
- It's Keats.
- Now, I'll be...
是雪莱的 我大约10分钟后回来
It's Shelley. I'll be back in about 10 minutes.
基茨
Keats.
我准你退下了
You have my permission to withdraw.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
- 怎么样？
- 没有任何踪迹 阁下
- Well?
- No trace, Your Excellency.
庭院里你搜过了吗？
Have you searched the grounds?
每英寸都搜过了 长官 从阁楼到地下室都搜过了
Every inch, sir, from the attics to the cellar.
我要你用自己的名誉担保不把这事告诉任何人
I must put you on your honor not to speak of this to anyone.
我必须提醒你公主是王位的第一顺位继承人
I must remind you that the princess is the direct heir to the throne.
这件事必须保持绝密
This must be classified as top crisis secret.
- 你能向我保证吗？
- 是的 长官
- Have I your pledge?
- Yes, sir.
非常好
Very well.
现在我必须通知国王及王后
Now we must notify Their Majesties.
噢
Oh.
真开心
So happy.
我很荣幸
The pleasure's mine.
奇怪的丫头
Screwball.
大 使 馆 在 其 特 别 公 告 中 称
尊 贵 的 安 公 主 殿 下
身 体 忽 然 抱 恙 .
天呐！公主的采访
Holy smoke! The princess interview.
11:45
11:45.
美国通讯社
随时报导 一切新闻
罗马日报
美 国 版
安公主染疾；
记者招待会取消
嗨 乔
Hi, Joe.
- 早上好 乔
- 你好 亲爱的
- Good morning, Joe.
- Hello, honey.
亨尼西先生一直在找你
Mr. Hennessy has been looking for you.
非常感谢 亲爱的
Thanks a lot, hon.
进来！
Come in!
你在找我吗？
You've been looking for me?
刚才来上班？
Just coming to work?
谁 我吗？
Who, me?
我们这里是8:30上班
We start our days at 8:30 in this office.
我们要完成分配的任务...
We pick up our assignments...
我的任务昨晚就完成了
I picked mine up last night.
- 你指的那个任务？
- 公主的 11:45的那个
- What assignment was that?
- The princess. 11:45.
你已经采访过了？
You've already been to the interview?
当然 我刚回来
Sure. I just got back.
- 好吧 好吧 好吧 算我错怪你了
- 没事
- Well, well, well, all my apologies.
- It's all right.
- 采访很有趣吧
- 算不上 跟往常一样吧
- This is very interesting.
- No, just routine.
告诉我 告诉我 她回答了采访单上的全部问题吗？
Tell me, tell me, did she answer all the questions on the list?
噢 当然她都回答了 我把它们放在这里或者别的什么地方了
Well, of course she did. I've got them right here somewhere.
你用不着忙活了 我这里就有一份副本
Don't disturb yourself. I have a copy here.
公主殿下对建立欧洲联盟有何看法？
How did Her Highness react to the idea of a European federation?
她认为还不错
She thought it was just fine.
是吗？
She did?
嗯 她认为这将产生两方面的影响
Well, she thought that there'd be two effects.
两方面？
Two?
直接还有间接的影响
The direct and the indirect.
说得真不错
Remarkable.
当然 她认为间接影响没有直接影响来得那么直接
Naturally, she thought that the indirect would not be as direct as the direct.
- 就是说 来得没有那么快
- 不 不 不 不
- That is, not right away.
- No, no, no, no.
当然 要过段时间 噢 谁知道呢
Later on, of course, well, nobody knows.
噢 噢 噢 这说法很老练啊
Well, well, well, that was a shrewd observation.
他们在耍你 知道吗 这些皇室的小家伙们
They fool you, you know, these royal kids.
他们可不像我们想的那样只会在舞会上跳舞
They've got a lot more on the ball than we suspect.
她对各国今后的友好关系怎么看呢？
How did she feel about the future friendship of nations?
要看年轻人
Youth.
她认为年轻人
She felt that the youth of the world
必将引导世界走向更美好的未来
must lead the way to a better world.
蛮新颖的
Original.
顺便问下 她当时穿的什么？
By the way, what was she wearing?
你是说 她当时着的什么装吗？
You mean, what did she have on?
还能是什么意思
That's usually what it means.
怎么了？这里对你来说有点儿太热了吗？
What's the matter? Is it a little warm in here for you?
不 没有 我刚跑回来的 就这样
No, no. I just hurried over here, that's all.
当然了 拿着这样不得了的料[自然要跑快点儿]
Naturally, with a story of these dimensions.
你刚说她穿的是灰色的？
Did you say she was wearing gray?
不 我没那么说过
No, I didn't say that.
嗯 她通常都穿灰色的
Well, she usually wears gray.
噢 是灰色的
Well, it was a kind of a gray.
我想我知道你说的是哪件连衣裙 衣领是金色的那件
I think I know the dress you mean. It has a gold collar.
就是那件 就是那件 没错
That's the one. That's the one, yeah.
我不知道该怎么去描述它 不过...
I didn't know exactly how to describe it, but that's...
我想你已经把它描述得很清楚了
I think you described it very well,
事实上公主殿下
in view of the fact that Her Highness
今天凌晨3:00突染疾病
was taken violently ill at 3:00 this morning,
正躺在床上发着高烧
put to bed with a high fever,
她今天所有的预订活动全部都取消了！
and has had all her appointments for today canceled in toto!
全部？
In toto?
是的 布兰德利先生 全部
Yes, Mr. Bradley, in toto.
这还真有点儿难咽[之前从门外秘书顺的饼干]
It's certainly pretty hard to swallow.
- 鉴于你刚从她那儿回来
- 没错
- In view of the fact that you just left her,
- of course.
你看看这些 布兰德利先生
But here it is, Mr. Bradley,
罗马所有的报纸头版都登了
all over the front page of every newspaper in Rome.
好吧 好吧 我睡过头了 谁都会睡过头的
All right, all right, I overslept. It can happen to anybody.
要是你起得够早 有时间读下今天早上的报纸
If you only got up early enough to read a morning paper,
你也许不会看到什么新闻事件
you might discover little news events,
或是娱乐大众的八卦
little items of general interest
但至少不会让人看过之后被
that might prevent someone in the future from getting immersed
这样一个镀着金的 精心包装 闪闪发光的谎话骗得晕头转向
in such a gold-plated, triple-decked, star-spangled lie
比如你刚才跟我说的那个
as you have just told me.
如果我是你 我就会试着干点儿别的工作
If I were you, I would try some other line of business,
比如床垫测试
like mattress testing.
这就是公主？
Is this the princess?
是的 布兰德利先生 这就是公主
Yes, Mr. Bradley, that is the princess.
不是安妮 奥克莱 桃勒西 拉莫 也不是蒋介石夫人
[安妮 奥克莱 1860-1926 美国著名神枪手 首位美国女明星]
[桃勒西 拉莫 1914-1996 美国演员及歌手]
[Chiang Kai-Shek 蒋介石 曾有某部二战书中一直译为蒋凯申]
It isn't Annie Oakley, Dorothy Lamour, or Madam Chiang Kai-Shek.
[Annie Oakley 1860-1926 American sharpshooter the first American female superstar]
[Dorothy Lamour 1914-1996 American actress and singer]
好好看清楚她的样子
Take a good look at her.
说不定哪天你还得采访她
You might be interviewing her again someday.
我被炒了吗？
Am I fired?
没有 你没有被炒
No, you're not fired.
我要炒你的时候 你都不用问
When I want to fire you, you won't have to ask.
你就知道自己被炒掉了！
[即登报 甚至可能在讣告栏：布兰德利 你被炒了！]
You'll know you're fired!
那家伙疯了
The man's mad.
乔万尼 我是乔 布兰德利
Giovanni, it's Joe Bradley.
现在 仔细听好了 我要你马上去我的房间
Now, listen carefully. I want you to hurry up to my place
去看看是不是还有人睡在那儿
and see if there's somebody there asleep.
好吧 乔先生 我这就去看
Say, Mr. Joe, I look.
你等着
You wait.
乔先生？
Mr. Joe?
我在！喂 喂 喂 跟我说 跟我说
Yeah! Yeah, yeah, yeah. Tell me. Tell me.
乔万尼 我爱你 好了 听着
Giovanni, I love you. Now, listen.
什么事 乔先生？
Yes, Mr. Joe?
拿把枪？
A gun?
不！
No!
好吧 拿把枪 拿把刀 拿什么都行
Yes, a gun, a knife, anything,
但别让任何人进出
but nobody goes in and nobody goes out.
好的
Okay.
你还没走？
You still here?
要是对这个女人真的做个采访值多少钱？
How much would a real interview with this dame be worth?
你是指公主殿下吗？
Are you referring to Her Highness?
我说的不是安妮 奥克莱 桃勒西 拉莫 或者...
I'm not referring to Annie Oakley, Dorothy Lamour or...
多少钱？
How much?
你问这干什么？你能采访到的机会...
What do you care? You got about as much chance as...
我知道 可要是我办到了 值多少钱？
I know, but if I did, how much would it be worth?
光简单的跟她谈下世界局势就值250
Just a plain talk on world conditions might be worth 250.
她对服装的品味 当然 就更值钱了 应该值1,000吧
Her views on clothes, of course, would be worth a lot more, maybe 1,000.
- 美元？
- 美元
- Dollars?
- Dollars.
我说的是她对所有事的看法
I'm talking about her views on everything.
公主私密的渴望
The private and secret longings of a princess.
她内心深处的想法
Her innermost thoughts,
将透露给你的罗马通讯记者 这是私人的 面对面的 独家采访
as revealed to your Rome correspondent in a private, personal, exclusive interview.
这点子不行吗 嗯？
Can't use it, huh?
我就知道你不会喜欢的
I didn't think you'd like it.
过来
Come here.
还有 爱情观了 我想？
Love angle, too, I suppose?
详细到所有的爱情观
Practically all love angle.
要附照片
With pictures.
可以的话 多少钱？
Could be. How much?
这么详细的料对任何通讯社来说都值5,000
That particular story will be worth five grand to any news service.
不过告诉我 布兰德利先生 要是你清醒的话
But tell me, Mr. Bradley, if you are sober,
你要怎样去完成这个不可思议的采访？
just how you are going to obtain this fantastic interview.
我打算装扮成一支体温计进入她的病房
I plan to enter her sickroom disguised as a thermometer.
你说的是5,000？我要和你握手约定
You said five grand? I want you to shake on that.
你知道吗 当然 今天公主殿下是躺在床上
And you realize, of course, Her Highness is in bed today
但明天就要离开去雅典了？
and leaves for Athens tomorrow?
知道
Yep.
既然这样 我还想再跟你打个赌
Now, I'd like to make a little side bet with you.
500 赌你弄不回来那份料
500 says you don't come up with the story.
你看那个做什么？
What are you looking at that for?
我只是想看看现在什么时候了
I just want to see what time it is.
- 嗯？
- 看下今天几号了
- Huh?
- What day it is.
就这么说定了！
It's a deal!
我们握手吧
Now I'd like you to shake.
在我看来 你这500已经是我的了
Let's see, you're into me for about 500 now.
要是你输了 你就欠我1,000
When you lose this bet, you'll owe me 1,000.
为什么 你这卑鄙的骗子 我当然会赢你
Why, you poor sucker, I'll practically own you.
到现在你已经套了我好多年了
You have practically owned me for a couple of years now.
不过现在都结束了
But that's all over.
我会赢了那笔钱
I'm going to win that money,
然后 我会用它给自己买张回纽约的单程机票
and with it, I'm gonna buy me a one-way ticket back to New York.
接着说 接着说 我就爱听你发牢骚
Go on, go on, I love to hear you whine.
等我到了一家真正的新闻编辑部的时候 我会很高兴想到
And when I'm back in a real newsroom, I'll enjoy thinking about you,
你坐在这儿 手里皮带那头的项圈里什么也没有
sitting here with an empty leash in your hands
再没人会在你面前瑟瑟发抖
and nobody to twitch for you.
再见了 鸽子！[鸽子 咕咕咕 话多且无意义]
So long, pigeon!
[知道意大利为什么出黑手党了吧？]
嘿 乔 你知道什么吗？
Hey, Joe. What you know?
一切都还好吗 乔万尼？
Is everything okay, Giovanni?
没人来找她 她也没出去
Nobody she's come. Nobody she's go.
绝对没人进出过
Absolutely nobody.
干得漂亮 太谢谢了
Swell. Thanks a lot.
乔万尼...
Giovanni...
你想赚点儿钱吗？
How would you like to make some money?
- 钱？
- 是的
- Money?
- Yeah.
这就对了 好了 听着 我有个方法绝对能赚钱
That's the stuff. Now, look, I've got a sure thing.
两天之内让你的钱翻一倍
Double your money back in two days.
让我的钱翻一倍？
Double my money?
是的 嗯 我需要点儿启动资金
Yeah, well, I need a little investment capital to swing the deal.
好了 要是你能借我一点儿钱...
Now, if you'll just lend me a little cash...
你还欠我两个月的房租呢
You owing me two months' rent,
你还想我借钱给你？
and you want me to lend you money?
- 是的
- 不行
- Yeah.
- No.
明天你会后悔的
Tomorrow you'll be sorry.
[这个动作让译者想起一个词：斯德哥尔摩综合症]
公主殿下？
Your Highness?
Your Royal Highness?
嗯 怎么了？
Yes, what is it?
亲爱的博纳科温医生...
Dear Dr. Bonnachoven...
是我 是的 噢 你没事了 好多了 你想要点儿什么吗？
Sure, yes, well, you're fine. Much better. Is there anything you want?
好多东西
So many things.
- 是吗？那好 跟医生说吧
- 好...
- Yes? Well, tell the doctor.
- So...
把一切都告诉医生吧
Tell the good doctor everything.
我梦见 我梦见
I dreamt, and I dreamt.
什么？好了 你梦见什么了？
Yes? Well, what did you dream?
我梦见自己睡在街道上 然后来了一个年轻的男人
I dreamt I was asleep in the street, and a young man came.
他长得高大又强壮 而且他对我很有意
He was tall and strong, and he was so mean to me.
是吗？
He was?
那感觉太好了
It was wonderful.
早上好
Good morning.
[注意嘴角那微微一颤 NICE!]
博纳科温医生呢？
Where's Dr. Bonnachoven?
我恐怕自己认识的人里没叫那个名字的
I'm afraid I don't know anybody by that name.
刚才同我说话的不是他吗？
Wasn't I talking to him just now?
我恐怕不是
Afraid not.
我是出了什么事故吗？
Have I had an accident?
不是
No.
我可以坐起来吗？[原文意思认为自己出了意外身体不能动]
Quite safe for me to sit up?
完全可以
Perfect.
谢谢
Thank you.
这些是你的吗？[这一段的表演相当精彩]
Are these yours?
你丢了什么吗？
Did you lose something?
没有
No.
你能告诉我 我这是在什么地方吗？
Would you be so kind as to tell me where I am?
噢 让您见笑了 这是我的公寓
Well, this is what is laughingly known as my apartment.
你是强行把我带到这儿来的吗？
Did you bring me here by force?
不 不 不 恰恰相反
No, no, no. Quite the contrary.
我整晚都在这里 一个人？
Have I been here all night, alone?
要是不算上我的话 是的
If you don't count me, yes.
这么说我整晚都同你在这里？
So I've spent the night here with you?
噢 好了 我的确不知道自己该怎么说
Well, now, I don't know that I'd use those words, exactly,
不过从某种角度上来说 是的
but from a certain angle, yes.
[这一段的面部表情 SO NICE!]
[亲爱的 那颗犬齿算是龅牙吗？请脑残粉务必恕译者无罪]
你好
How do you do?
- 你是...
- 布兰德利 乔 布兰德利
- And you are...
- Bradley. Joe Bradley.
很高兴认识你
Delighted.
你不会知道能认识您我有多么高兴
You don't know how delighted I am to meet you.
你可以坐下了
You may sit down.
非常感谢[流氓 你就没看人家手指的哪边吗？]
Thank you very much.
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
你就叫我安雅吧
You may call me Anya.
谢谢 安雅
Thank you, Anya.
你要来杯咖啡吗？
Would you like a cup of coffee?
- 现在什么时候了？
- 快1:30了
- What time is it?
- About 1:30.
1:30！我必须换上衣服离开了！
1:30! I must get dressed and go!
为什么？你这么急为什么？时间还多着呢
Why? What's your hurry? There's lots of time.
不 没时间了 我给你带来的麻烦已经够多了
No, there isn't, and I've been quite enough trouble to you as it is.
麻烦？
Trouble?
我不觉得你有什么麻烦到我
You're not what I'd call trouble.
我没有吗？
I'm not?
我去给你准备沐浴
I'll run a bath for you.
你可以进去了
There you are.
现在我们开始
Here we go now.
就这样别动 姿势很好
There you are. That does it.
别拉那么紧 好吗？
Give me a little slack, will you?
艾文！你为什么不接电话？
Irving! Why don't you answer the phone?
听着 我是乔
Look, this is Joe.
艾文 你能在5分钟内赶过来吗？
Irving, can you get over here in about five minutes?
不行 我现在过不来 乔 我正忙着呢
No, I can't come now, Joe. I'm busy.
不行
No.
乔 我没工夫听电话
Joe, I'm up to my ears in work.
去换上你的下一套服装 好吗 亲爱的？独木舟
Go and get into your next outfit, will you, honey? The canoe.
是什么样的独家新闻 乔？
What kind of a scoop, Joe?
听着 艾文 在电话里我可不能说
Look, Irving, I can't talk over the telephone.
要是说漏了一个词
One word in the wrong quarter,
这事就会捅上天去
and this whole thing might blow sky-high.
这是上头版的料 我只能告诉你这么多了
It's front-page stuff. That's all I can tell you.
可能是政治性的 或者可能是件轰动的丑闻
It might be political or it might be a sensational scandal.
我还不确定 总之是猛料
I'm not sure which, but it's a big story.
需要附上些照片
It's got to have pictures.
可我现在不能过来 乔 我很忙...
But I can't come now, Joe. I'm busy...
我很忙现在 半小时后我还要去Rocca咖啡馆同弗朗西斯卡见面
I'm busy now, and I'm meeting Francesca at Rocca's in a half an hour.
听不懂
Don't understand.
你在这里
There you are.
我在看附近的那些人们
I was looking at all the people out here.
住在这样的地方一定很有意思
It must be fun to live in a place like this.
是的 有时候是很有意思
Yeah, it has its moments.
我可以向你介绍每间公寓的主人
I can give you a running commentary on each apartment.
我必须走了
I must go.
我只是在等着和你说声再见
I only waited to say good-bye.
再见？为什么 我们才刚认识
Good-bye? Why, we've only just met.
- 要吃点儿早餐吗？
- 抱歉 我没时间了
- How about some breakfast?
- I'm sorry. I haven't time.
什么都不吃就急着走 那一定是非常重要的约会
It must be a pretty important date to run off without eating.
是的
It is.
好吧 我陪你去 不管你去哪儿
Well, I'll go along with you, wherever you are going.
没关系 谢谢 我自己能去
That's all right, thank you. I can find the place.
谢谢你让我睡在你的床上
Thank you for letting me sleep in your bed.
没关系的 这不算什么
That's all right. Think nothing of it.
你真是太体贴了
It was very considerate of you.
你在躺椅上一定非常不舒服
You must have been awfully uncomfortable on that couch.
不 我一直都睡躺椅上！
No. Do it all the time!
- 再见 布兰德利先生
- 再见
- Good-bye, Mr. Bradley.
- Good-bye.
从那里穿过去 然后沿阶梯下到尽头
Go right through there and down all the steps.
谢谢
Thank you.
噢 世界真小
Well, small world.
是的 我差点儿忘了 你能借我些钱吗？
Yes. I almost forgot. Can you lend me some money?
好的 可以 你昨晚身上就没带钱 对吧？
Yeah, that's right. You didn't have any last night, did you?
你要多少钱？
How much was it that you wanted?
噢 我不知道自己要多少 你身上有多少？
Well, I don't know how much I need. How much have you got?
嗯 我想我们就五五分吧 这是1,000里拉
Well, suppose we just split this 50-50? Here's 1,000 lira.
1,000？你真的要给我这么多吗？
1,000? Can you really spare all that?
这大概相当于$1.50美元
It's about $1.50.
噢 我会让人把它送还给你的
Well, I'll arrange for it to be sent back to you.
你的地址呢？
What is your adress?
玛古塔大道51号
Via Margutta 51.
乔 布兰德利
Joe Bradley.
再见 谢谢
Good-bye. Thank you.
让我的钱翻一倍 嗯？
Double my money, eh?
你告诉我这样怎么能让我的钱翻一倍？
You tell me why double my money that way?
明天 明天
Tomorrow, tomorrow.
是啊 明天
Yeah, tomorrow.
你的发质好极了
What a wonderful hair you have.
剪短 谢谢
Just cut, thank you.
剪短？
Just cut?
噢 那么 剪到这里？
Well, then, cut so?
高一点儿
Higher.
高一点儿？
Higher?
这样？
Here?
再高点
More.
- 这样？
- 还要再高点
- Here?
- Even more.
那要剪到哪儿？
Where?
这儿
There.
这儿？
There?
你确定吗 小姐？
Are you sure, miss?
我非常确定 谢谢
I'm quite sure, thank you.
全剪掉？
All off?
全剪掉
All off.
剪掉
Off.
- 你确定吗？
- 是的
- Are you sure?
- Yes.
好吧
Yes.
剪掉！
Off!
剪掉
Off.
剪掉！
Off!
你这袖珍相机真不错
That's a nice little camera you have there.
是不错
It's nice.
你不会介意把它借给我一下 对吧？
You don't mind if I just borrow it, do you?
- 维柏女士！
- 马上就还你
- Miss Weber!
- Bring it right back.
- 就用几分钟
- 不行
- Just for a couple of minutes.
- No.
放手 这是我的相机
Let go. It's my camera.
你是音乐家 是吗？
You musician, maybe?
你是艺术家？
You artist?
画家？
Painter?
我知道了 你是模特
I know. You model.
模特
Model.
谢谢
Thank you.
好极了
It's perfect.
你留短发也很好看
You be nice without long hair.
这发型很酷 你觉得酷吗？
Now is cool. Cool?
是的 这就是我想要的发型
Yes. It's just what I wanted.
好了 你今晚干嘛不来和我跳个舞呢？
Now, why you not come dancing tonight with me?
你该来看看 很不错的
You should see. Is so nice.
就在圣安杰洛[城堡]旁 台伯河的一条船上
Is on a boat on the Tiber, the river by Sant'Angelo.
月光 音乐 浪漫
Moonlight, music, romantic.
非常 非常...非常！[意大利人就会这么点儿英语]
Is very, very... Very!
好吗？你来吗？
Please? You come?
我很想去
I wish I could.
不过你的朋友 我不认为他们能认出你
But your friend, I not think they recognize you.
是的 我不认为他们会认出我
No, I don't think they will.
- 非常感谢
- 谢谢
- Thank you very much.
- Thank you.
9:00过后 我会在那儿 在河上跳舞
After 9:00, I will be there, dancing on river.
记住 圣安杰洛
Remember, Sant'Angelo.
我所有的朋友...
All my friends...
要是你能来 你就是那儿最漂亮的女孩儿
If you come, you will be most pretty of all girl.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 再见
- Good-bye.
谢谢
Thank you.
1,000里拉
1,000 lira.
我没钱了
No money.
抱歉 我真的没有钱了
I'm sorry. I've really no money.
你看
Look.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
噢 是你
Well, it's you.
是你 布兰德利先生
Yes, Mr. Bradley.
怎么了？
Or is it?
你喜欢吗？
Do you like it?
是的 非常喜欢
Yeah. Very much.
这就是你的秘密约会吧
So that was your mysterious appointment.
布兰德利先生 我要向你忏悔
Mr. Bradley, I have a confession to make.
表白？[表白同上句忏悔用词相同]
Confession?
是的 我昨晚是偷跑出来的 从学校
Yes. I ran away last night, from school.
怎么了？
What was the matter?
和老师闹矛盾了？
Trouble with the teacher?
不 不是因为那种事
No, nothing like that.
噢 你不会无缘无故就从学校偷跑出来吧
Well, you don't just run away from school for nothing.
我本想就偷跑出来一两个小时
I only meant it to be for an hour or two.
他们昨晚给我用了一些让我睡觉的药
They gave me something last night to make me sleep.
我明白了
I see.
我现在最好还是乘出租车回去了
Now I'd better get a taxi and go back.
噢 听我说 在你这么做之前
Well, look, before you do,
为什么不再玩一会儿呢？
why don't you take a little time for yourself?
那就再玩一个小时吧
Maybe another hour.
生活充满了未知数 玩个一整天吧
Live dangerously. Take the whole day.
我可以做些我一直都想做的事
I could do some of the things I've always wanted to.
比如？
Like what?
你想都想不到的
You can't imagine.
我想一整天都做自己喜欢的事情
I'd like to do just whatever I like the whole day long.
你是说 像是剪短头发 吃冰淇淋这样的事情？
You mean, things like having your hair cut, eating gelato?
是的 我想坐在路边咖啡馆 看商店橱窗里的东西
Yes, and I'd like to sit at a sidewalk cafe and look in shop windows,
在雨中漫步
walk in the rain.
做一些好玩 甚至有些刺激的事
Have fun, and maybe some excitement.
- 这些对你来说不算什么 对吧？
- 很不错
- Doesn't seem much to you, does it?
- It's great.
这么跟你说吧
Tell you what.
我们为什么不一起做这些事情呢？
Why don't we do all those things together?
你不用工作吗？
Don't you have to work?
工作？不用 今天放假
Work? No. Today's going to be a holiday.
可你不会想要做一大堆愚蠢的事情的
But you don't want to do a lot of silly things.
我会不想吗？
Don't I?
第一件想做的事 去家路边咖啡馆 这就走吧
First wish, one sidewalk cafe. Coming right up.
我正好知道个地方 Rocca咖啡馆
[译者忽然想起卡萨布兰卡的瑞克咖啡馆]
I know just the place. Rocca's.
要是学校里的人看到你新剪的头发他们会怎么说？
What will the people at school say when they see your new haircut?
他们会大吃一惊的
They'll have a fit.
要是他们知道我整晚都在你的房间里他们会说什么呢？
What would they say if they knew I'd spent the night in your room?
噢 我告诉你吧 你不能告诉你的朋友 我也不会告诉我的朋友
Well, I tell you what. You don't tell your folks, and I won't tell mine.
就这么说定了
It's a pact.
好了 你想喝什么？
Well, what would you like to drink?
香槟 谢谢
Champagne, please.
香槟？
Champagne?
给我来杯冰咖啡
And cold coffee for me.
你在那所学校里一定过着奢华的生活
Must be quite a life you have in that school.
午饭喝香槟
Champagne for lunch.
只有在特别的场合才喝
Only on special occasions.
比如说？
For instance?
最近一次是在我父亲的周年纪念日
The last time was my father's anniversary.
结婚纪念日？
Weding?
不是 纪念他从事工作40周年
No. It was the 40th anniversary of the day he got his job.
40年都在从事一份工作 你对他的工作知道多少？
Forty years on the job. What do you know about that?
他是干什么的？
What does he do?
嗯 最接近的说法应该叫公共关系吧
Well, mostly you might call it public relations.
噢 那工作挺辛苦的
Well, that's hard work.
- 是的 我不在意他的工作
- 那他呢？
- Yes, I wouldn't care for it.
- Does he?
我曾听到他抱怨自己的工作
I've heard him complain about it.
他为什么不辞职呢？
Why doesn't he quit?
噢 干那行的人几乎就不能辞职
Well, people in that line of work almost never do quit,
除非他们的健康状况真的恶化到无法继续工作
unless it's actually unhealthy for them to continue.
噢 那 祝他身体健康
Well, here's to his health, then.
知道吗 每个人都这么说
You know, that's what everybody says.
味道还好吗？
It's all right?
还好 谢谢
Yes, thank you.
你做什么工作的？
What is your work?
我卖东西的
I'm in the selling game.
真的吗？听起来很有意思
Really? How interesting.
你都卖什么？
What do you sell?
肥料
Fertilizer.
化学品 你知道吗 化学品
Chemicals. You know, chemicals.
类似的东西
Stuff like that.
艾文！噢 见到你真高兴！
Irving! Well, am I glad to see you!
高兴什么？你又忘了带钱包吗？
Why? Did you forget your wallet?
搬把椅子过来 艾文 跟我们坐一起
Pull up a chair, Irving. Sit down with us.
你不打算跟我介绍一下吗？
Aren't you going to introduce me?
噢 这位是我的一位非常好的朋友 艾文 拉多维奇 这是安雅 艾文
Yes. This is a very good friend of mine, Irving Radovich. Anya, Irving.
- 安雅...
- 史密斯
- Anya...
- Smith.
你好 史密蒂
Hiya, Smitty.
真迷人
Charmed.
嘿 有没有人跟你说过你长得超像...
[在安听来是 你是位相当ringer...]
Hey, anybody ever tell you you're a dead ringer for...
噢 我想我该走了
[有个智力缺陷的朋友真是悲哀啊]
Well, I guess I'll be going.
不 别这样 艾文 坐下吧 和我们坐一起 和我们坐一起
No, don't do anything like that, Irving. Sit down. Join us. Join us.
噢 那就等弗朗西斯卡来了再走吧
Well, just till Francesca gets here.
告诉我 拉多维奇先生 什么是ringer？
Tell me, Mr. Radovich, what is a ringer?
服务生？
Waiter?
这是个美国短语
It's an American term,
意思是说某个人非常的有魅力 迷人
and it means anyone who has a great deal of charm.
- 谢谢
- 你客气了
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
我表妹
Cousins.
布兰德利先生刚告诉了我他的工作
Mr. Bradley's just been telling me all about his work.
我真高兴听你这么说
[为好朋友终于找女朋友高兴？]
I'd like to have heard that.
你是做什么的？
What do you do?
我跟乔干的是同一行 只是我...
I'm in the same racket as Joe, only I'm...
我非常抱歉 艾文
I'm awfully sorry, Irving.
- 你这是...
- 抱歉
- What are you...
- I'm sorry.
听着 我还是懂得起的 再见了
Look, I can take a hint. I'll see you around.
你的饮料才刚来
Your drink's just here.
噢 你的饮料正好来了 艾文 别急着走
Yeah, here's your drink right now, Irving. Take it easy.
我对刚才的事很抱歉 坐下吧 他人很不错的
I'm sorry about that. Sit down. That's a good fellow.
喝杯...这才是好孩子
Have a... That's a boy.
你...
You're...
你在拧我的手臂 你知道的
You're twisting my arm, you know.
当心点儿别再弄洒就好了
Just be a little more careful not to spill.
弄洒？刚才是谁弄洒的？
Spill? Who's been doing the spilling?
你
You.
- 我？
- 是的
- Me?
- Yeah.
你在哪儿找到的这个疯子？
Where did you find this loony?
没有说你 敬你一杯
You're okay. Here's to you.
致以我最美好的祝愿
Here's hoping for the best.
要不是因为这发型 我发誓...
If it wasn't for that hair, I'd swear that...
谢谢
Thanks.
你滑倒了 艾文 你滑倒了 你刚才差点儿伤着自己
You slipped, Irving. You slipped, you almost hurt yourself that time.
我滑倒了？我差点儿伤着自己？
I slipped? I almost hurt myself?
- 乔 我不是滑倒的！
- 你一定扭伤得不轻
- Joe, I didn't slip!
- You've got a bad sprain there.
别管我扭伤得怎样 乔
Never mind I got a bad sprain, Joe.
我们最好到那边去把衣服弄干净
We'd better go in here and get it fixed up.
- 正好 我也想...
- 我们能失陪一会儿吗？
- Yeah, I'd like to...
- Will you excuse us for a minute?
好的 当然可以 我非常抱歉
Yes, of course. I'm so sorry.
- 过来 朋友
- 乔 你先别忙
- Come here, pal.
- Joe, now wait a minute.
你这是想干什么？把你的手从我身上拿开
What are you trying to do now? Take your hands off me.
- 你有带打火机吗？
- 要那个东西干什么？
- Have you got your lighter?
- What's that got to do with it?
- 你有带吗？
- 是的 可你要拿去干什么？
- Have you got it?
- Yeah, but what are you trying to do?
听着 给你5,000你愿意吗？
Listen, what would you do for five grand?
- 5,000？
- 好的 听着
- Five grand?
- Okay, look.
她不知道我是谁也不知道我是干什么的
She doesn't know who I am or what I do.
听着 艾文 这就是我说的料 是我发掘的 我得保住它
Look, Irving, this is my story. I dug it up. I've got to protect it.
她真的就是...
She's really the...
你的相片会让这个短暂的史诗般的作品升值一倍
Your tintypes are gonna make this little epic twice as valuable.
- “公主前往贫民区访问”
- 赚的钱你拿25%
- "The princess goes slumming."
- You're in for 25% of the take.
- 这能赚5,000
- 最少这个数 亨尼西已经保证出这个价
- The take's five Gs.
- Minimum. Hennessy shook hands on it.
- 那就是$1,500美元
- 是$1,250美元[脑子钝就是坑爹啊]
- That's $1,500.
- It's $1,250.
好的 现在握手吧
Okay. Now you shake.
好的 现在借我30,000
Okay, now lend me 30,000.
30,000？那可是50美元 你这是要买王冠吗？
30,000? That's 50 bucks. Are you gonna buy the crown jewels?
她正在那儿喝香槟 我没钱结账了
She's out there now drinking champagne that I can't pay for.
我们得逗她开心 对吧？
We've got to entertain her, don't we?
乔 我们不能带着这么惹眼的公主在城里到处转悠
Joe, we can't go running around town with a hot princess.
你到底想不想做这笔交易了？
Do you want in on this deal or don't you?
周六把钱还我
This I want back Saturday.
好的 你的打火机呢？
Okay. Now where's your lighter?
我们开始干吧
Let's go to work.
好点儿了吗？
Better now?
- 你的耳朵
- 我的耳朵？
- Your ear.
- My ear?
是的 乔给我弄好了
Yeah. Joe fixed it.
你介意抽支烟吗？
Would you care for a cigarette?
好的 请给我吧
Yes, please.
你也许不相信 但我这真是第一次
You won't believe this, but it's my very first.
你第一次？
Your very first?
学校不准吸烟吗？
No smoking in school?
你的第一支香烟
Your first cigarette.
好了 这小东西弄好了
There. The gizmo works.
噢 感觉怎么样？还好吗？
Well, what's the verdict? Okay?
没什么感觉
Nothing to it.
这就对了 没什么感觉
That's right. Nothing to it.
我要伸一下腿
I'll stretch my legs a little here.
这次我请客 艾文
I'll pick this one up, Irving.
是啊 你付得起
Yeah. You can afford it.
好了 接下来我们干什么呢？我们要稍微做个时间表吗？
Well, what shall we do next? Shall we make out a little schedule?
别说那个词 拜托
Not that word, please.
我说的不是工作...学校时间表
I didn't mean a work... School schedule.
我说的是娱乐时间表
I meant a fun schedule.
好的 我们走吧
Yes. Let's just go.
噢 你怎么样 艾文？你准备好了吗？
Well, how about you, Irving? Are you ready?
- 是的
- 那走吧
- Yeah.
- Let's go.
弗朗西斯卡！
Francesca!
- 这位是...
- 史密蒂
- This is...
- Smitty.
她可是位千金小姐 艾文 千金
She's a grand girl, Irving. Grand.
5,000 艾文
Five grand, Irving.
- 乔！
- 你这是要去哪儿？
- Joe!
- Where are you going now?
亲爱的 我要开始工作了 我晚上再给你电话
Honey, I gotta work. I'll call you tonight.
看看那些家伙！
Look at those men!
他们应该别那么引人注意的
They were supposed to be inconspicuous.
是你要求穿便装的
You asked for plain clothes.
嘿！抱歉
Hey! Excuse me.
嘿！停下！骑着VESPA回来！
Hey! Stop! Come back with your VESPA here!
- 让我来...
- 不 不 让我来 我可以开的
- Let me take this...
- No, no. Let it go. I can do it.
[译者忽然觉得李刚他儿子有点儿冤 要是他爹就给他买个VESPA的话...]
美 国 通 讯 社
噢
Yeah.
从现在起我要改过自新了
I'm going straight from now on.
美国通讯社？他什么意思？
American News Service? What did he mean?
噢 知道吗 要是你说自己是新闻界的
Well, you know, you say you're with the press,
任何麻烦你都能躲过去的
you can get away with anything.
骑着[VESPA]摩托车去教堂结婚吧 了不起的家伙
Going to church to get married on a scooter, that's a hot one.
乔相当会说谎
Joe's a wonderful liar.
恭喜 恭喜
Congratulations. Congratulations.
你不用这么担心 我不会要你娶我的
You don't have to look so worried. I won't hold you to it.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
你也没必要这么高兴吧！
You don't have to be too grateful!
好的 我没有
Okay, I won't.
我也很能说谎 对吧 布兰德利先生？
I'm a good liar, too, aren't I, Mr. Bradley?
是我认识的人里最棒的
The best I ever met.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
我说...
Say...
跟我来吧
Come with me.
诚实之口
[也译为真实之口 位于罗马科斯梅丁圣母堂]
The mouth of truth.
[Ita：Bocca della Verità-Basilica of Santa Maria in Cosmedin]
传说中要是你把手放在这里并说谎的话
The legend is that if you're given to lying and put your hand in there,
手就会被咬掉
[这个传说自其17世纪出土后出现]
it'll be bitten off.
这真可怕
What a horrid idea.
你试试看
Let's see you do it.
好吧
Sure.
你好
Hello.
你这个坏蛋！
You beast!
你根本就没事！你的手根本就没有受伤！
It was perfectly all right! You never hurt your hand!
抱歉 开个玩笑而已
I'm sorry. It's just a joke.
你的手根本就没有受伤
You never hurt your hand.
抱歉 你没事吧？
I'm sorry. You okay?
- 是的
- 那好 我们走吧
- Yes.
- All right. Let's go.
小心！
Look out!
[译者趋同于这是古罗马的下水道井盖的说法]
[各位观众是不是觉得有些冷？]
我去把车停在那个墙角
I'll park at the corner.
这些题字 是要表达什么意思？
What do they mean, all these inscriptions?
噢 每一个都代表着实现了一个愿望
Well, each one represents a wish fulfilled.
这始于大战期间一次空袭的时候
It all started during the war when there was an air raid right out here,
一个男人同自己的四个孩子被困在街上
a man with his four children was caught in the street.
他们跑到这堵墙边寻求庇护
They ran over against the wall right there for shelter
祈祷自己能够平安
and prayed for safety.
炸弹就掉在非常近的地方 可没有一个人受伤
Bombs fell very close, but no one was hurt.
后来 这个男人回到这里 挂上了第一个纪念牌
Later on, the man came back and he put up the first of these tablets.
从那时起 这里就成为了一个圣地
Since then, it's become a sort of a shrine.
人们到这里来 等到他们的愿望实现的时候
People come, and whenever their wishes are granted,
他们就会再挂上这样一个小瓷片
they put up another one of these little plaques.
很美的故事
Lovely story.
看看这些题字吧
Read some of the inscriptions.
要许愿吗？
Make a wish?
还是跟医生说吗？
Tell the doctor?
不管怎样 愿望能实现的机会都微乎其微
Anyway, the chances of it being granted are very slight.
噢 现在去哪儿呢？
Well, what now?
我知道一个好地方 可以在船上跳舞
I've heard of a wonderful place for dancing on a boat.
你指的是 圣安杰洛[城堡]边的驳船？
[哈德良陵墓 现名圣安杰洛城堡 位于帕克 阿德里亚诺，罗马]
[罗马皇帝哈德良及其家人陵墓 台伯河右岸 建于公元130-139年]
You mean, the barges down by Sant'Angelo?
[The Mausoleum of Hadrian known as Castel Sant'Angelo in Parco Adriano, Rome]
[Roman Emperor Hadrian and his family's mausoleum, on the right bank of the Tiber, between 130-139 AD]
是的 我们今晚去不好吗？
Yes, couldn't we go there tonight?
- 为什么不呢？
- 只要是你想做的都行
- Why not?
- Anything you wish.
等到了午夜 我就会穿着我的水晶鞋乘上一辆南瓜车 离开的
And then at midnight, I'll turn into a pumpkin and drive away in my glass slipper.
那是童话故事的结局
And that'll be the end of the fairytale.
噢 我猜艾文现在得走了
Well, I guess Irving has to go now.
我吗？
I do?
是的 要知道 你还有单大业务要谈
Yes, you know, that big business development of yours
你不是得参加吗？
that you have to attend to?
噢 业务
Oh, the development.
没错 那可不能怠慢了
Yes, can't afford not to take care of that.
好吧 晚些时候再见 史密蒂
Yeah. I'll see you later, Smitty.
- 祝大业务谈判顺利
- 谢谢
- Good luck with the big development.
- Thanks.
两位 谢谢
Two, please.
[要是十三陵也这么闹的话...]
[据译者猜测这就是MEN IN BLACK的原型...]
[黑衣人穿黑西装系因将军要求尽量不引人注意]
你好
Hello.
布兰德利先生 要是你不介意我这么说的话
Mr. Bradley, if you don't mind my saying so,
我觉得你是个
ringer[按照布兰德利之前的胡诌 此处为有魅力的人]
I think you are a ringer.
什么？
A what?
噢！
Oh!
非常感谢
Thanks very much.
你整天都陪着我做我想做的事
You've spent the whole day doing things I've always wanted to.
为什么？
[公主一直都觉得你对她动了情]
Why?
我不知道 这是应该的
I don't know. It seemed the thing to do.
我从不知道有这么好的人
I've never heard of anybody so kind.
举手之劳
It wasn't any trouble.
如此的慷慨无私
Or so completely unselfish.
我们去吧台喝一杯吧
Let's have a drink at the bar.
你来了！
There you are!
我找你很久了 我还以为也许你不会来了
I look for you a long time. I think maybe you not come.
剪掉...都剪掉！
Off... All off!
短发很好看 对吧？
It's nice without, isn't it?
酷
Cool.
非常 非常好
[意大利人恶补英语就补出来个GOOD!]
Very, very good.
这位是布兰德利先生
This is Mr. Bradley.
我 马里奥 德兰尼
I, Mario Delani.
认识很久了吗？
Old friends?
是的 今天下午他给我剪的头发 他邀我今晚来这儿的
Yes. He cut my hair this afternoon. He invited me here tonight.
噢 你说你的名字是？
Well, what did you say the name was?
德兰尼 马里奥 德兰尼
Delani. Mario Delani.
马里奥 德兰尼 非常高兴认识你
Mario Delani. I'm very glad to know you.
我也是
Me, too.
我可以...可以...你介意吗？
May I enjoy myself... The pleasure... Do you mind?
不 不介意 请便吧
No, no. Go right ahead.
谢谢
Thank you.
- 我有错过什么吗？
- 你来得正是时候 朋友
- Did I miss anything?
- You're just in time, pal.
和史密蒂跳舞的那人是谁？
Who's Smitty dancing with?
理发师
The barber.
今天下午给她理发 今晚还约了她
Cut her hair this afternoon. Made a date for tonight.
公主和理发师
The princess and the barber.
怎么回事？
What is it?
奥伽斯
August.
谢谢！
Thank you!
再见
Bye.
公主殿下
Your Highness.
慢慢跳到入口那边去
You'll dance quietly towards the entrance.
那里有辆车在等着
There is a car waiting.
- 不
- 公主殿下 请吧
- No.
- Your Highness, please.
你弄错了
You've made a mistake.
放开我 你不肯放手吗？
Let me go. Will you let me go?
布兰德利先生！放开我 你不放手吗？布兰德利先生！
Mr. Bradley! Let me go, will you? Mr. Bradley!
放手！
Let go!
你...
You...
再给他一下 史密蒂！
Hit him again, Smitty!
- 乔 这是我的车钥匙
- 警察来了 警察来了 快走
- Joe, here are my car keys.
- The police. The police. Come on.
快到桥那边去
The other side of the bridge.
[无处不在的喵星人 哪怕只有个背影]
没事吧？
All right?
还好 你呢？
Fine. How are you?
没事
Fine.
你知道吗 你刚才真的好厉害
Say, you know, you were great back there.
你也不差啊
You weren't so bad yourself.
我想我们最好还是乘艾文的车离开这里吧
I guess we'd better get Irving's car and get out of here.
这是自罗马广播的美国时段节目
This is The American Hour from Rome,
现在继续我们的音乐精选节目
continuing our program of musical selections.
衣服都弄脏了吗？
Everything ruined?
没有 很快就能干了
No. They'll be dry in a minute.
很合身
Suits you.
你可以一直穿我的衣服
You should always wear my clothes.
看起来是这样的
It seems I do.
我想喝点儿酒应该会感觉好些的
I thought a little wine might be good.
我可以做些东西吃吗？
Shall I cook something?
没有厨房 也没有可以做的东西 我都在外面吃
No kitchen. Nothing to cook. I always eat out.
你喜欢这样吗？
Do you like that?
生活并不总是如人意的
Life isn't always what one likes.
是吗？
Is it?
是的 不是的
No, it isn't.
- 累了吗？
- 有一点儿
- Tired?
- A little.
你过了相当难忘的一天
You've had quite a day.
美妙的一天
A wonderful day.
这是自罗马广播的美国时段节目
This is The American Hour from Rome,
现在用英语及意大利语播送一条特别新闻简讯
broadcasting a special news bulletin in English and Italian.
截至今晚 仍旧没有卧病在床的安公主的进一步消息
Tonight, there is no further word from the bedside of Princess Ann in Rome,
她在欧洲贸易推动之旅的最后一站 罗马 昨日突染疾病
where she was taken ill yesterday on the last leg of her European goodwill tour.
外界传闻说她的病情可能很严重
This has given rise to rumors that her condition may be serious,
这在她的国民之中造成了恐慌和焦虑的情绪
which is causing alarm and anxiety among the people in her country.
- 明天再听新闻吧
- 好的
- The news can wait till tomorrow.
- Yes.
可以再给我倒点儿酒吗？
May I have a little more wine?
真抱歉我没能给我们做顿晚饭
I'm sorry I couldn't cook us some dinner.
你在学校学过怎么做饭吗？
Did you learn how in school?
我的厨艺很棒的
I'm a good cook.
我可以以此为生的
I could earn my living at it.
我还会针线 清洁房屋和熨衣服
I can sew, too, and clean a house and iron.
这些事情我都会
I learned to do all those things.
我只是没机会为谁做这些事罢了
I just haven't had the chance to do it for anyone.
噢 看来我该搬家了
Well, it looks like I'll have to move
我得给自己找间带厨房的屋子了
and get myself a place with a kitchen.
是的
Yes.
我该走了 现在
I shall have to go now.
安雅...
Anya...
有些事我想告诉你
There's something that I want to tell you.
别说了
No, please.
什么都别说
Nothing.
我必须换上衣服离开了
I must go and get dressed.
请在下一个转角处停车
Stop at the next corner, please.
好的
Okay.
是这里吗？
Here?
是的
Yes.
我得离开你了 现在
I have to leave you now.
我会走到那个转角然后转过去
I'm going to that corner there and turn.
你必须留在车里然后离开
You must stay in the car and drive away.
答应我过了转角就不要再看我
Promise not to watch me go beyond the corner.
只管开车离开 别管我
Just drive away and leave me,
就像我离开你那样
as I leave you.
好吧
All right.
我不知道该如何道别
I don't know how to say good-bye.
我不知道该说什么
I can't think of any words.
那就别说了
Don't try.
公主殿下 24个小时 不可能什么都没发生
Your Royal Highness, 24 hours, they can't all be blank.
当然不是
They are not.
可我该怎么同国王和王后解释呢？
But what explanation am I to offer Their Majesties?
我之前不舒服 现在我好多了
I was indisposed. I am better.
殿下 您必须理解我得履行自己的职责
Ma'am, you must appreciate that I have my duty to perform,
正如公主殿下也有她自己的职责
just as Your Royal Highness has her duty.
阁下 我相信您会发现今后没必要
Your Excellency, I trust you will not find it necessary
再说那样的话了
to use that word again.
要是我完全意识不到自己对家人和国民还负有责任的话
Were I not completely aware of my duty to my family and my country,
今晚我就不会回来了
I would not have come back tonight,
或者 应该说是 永远不会回来
or, indeed, ever again.
好了 我知道我们今天的时间表排得相当满
And now, since I understand we have a very full schedule today,
你们都可以退下了
you have my permission to withdraw.
不用端牛奶还有饼干了
No milk and crackers.
我没有什么吩咐了 谢谢 伯爵夫人
That will be all, thank you, Countess.
真的吗？你真的办到了吗？
Is it true? Did you really get it?
办到什么？
Did I get what?
公主的料啊 独家采访 你办到了吗？
The princess story. The exclusive. Did you get it?
不 没有 我没有办到
No, no, I didn't get it.
什么？这不可能
What? But that's impossible.
要喝杯咖啡或者别的吗？
Have a cup of coffee or something?
- 乔 你可不能瞒着我
- 谁要瞒着你了？
- Joe, you can't hold out on me.
- Who's holding out on you?
- 是你
- 你在胡说些什么？
- You are.
- What are you talking about?
我都知道
I know too much.
你先是走进我的办公室
First you come into my office
然后说要对公主做个独家采访
and ask about an exclusive on the princess.
接着 你就跑出去了
Next, you disappear.
之后我从自己在大使馆的关系那里听说
Then I get the rumor from my contact at the embassy
公主没有生病而是自己跑到城里来了
that the princess isn't sick at all and she's out on the town.
你还算得上是新闻工作者吗？
What kind of a newspaperman are you?
所有传到你耳朵里的毫无根据的传言你也信吗？
You believe every two-bit rumor that comes your way?
嗯 还有很多其他的传闻
Yeah, and a lot of other rumors
像是河边驳船上的舞会
about a shindig on a barge down by the river
还有来自某国的8名秘密情务人员被捕
and the arrest of eight Secret Service men from a country which shall be nameless.
之后就传出公主奇迹般康复的新闻
And then comes the news of the lady's miraculous recovery.
现在都满天飞了
It all ads up.
别给我抬杠 好抬高你手上料的价钱
And don't think by playing hard to get you'll raise the price of that story.
交易就是交易
A deal's a deal.
好了 快说吧 快说吧 你弄的料呢？
Now, come on, come on, where is that story?
我手上没有什么料
I have no story.
- 那之前你怎么会想到要...
- 乔！
- Then what was the idea of...
- Joe!
- 伙计 等你们看到这些
- 艾文...
- Man, wait till you see these.
- Irving...
你好 亨尼西先生 您来得正是时候
Hiya, Mr. Hennessy. You got here at the right time.
- 艾文...
- 等你看了...
- Irving...
- Wait till you get a look...
这是什么意思？
What's the idea?
你跑这里来把东西在我的房间里洒得到处都是想干什么？
What do you mean charging in here and spilling things all over my place?
谁洒得到处都是了？
Who's spilling?
就是你 我之前就这样跟你说过一次了
You did. I spoke to you about that once before.
你还记得吗？
Don't you remember?
乔 看看我的裤子
Joe, look at my pants.
噢 你最好进去吧裤子弄干 艾文
Yeah, you'd better come in here and dry them off, Irving.
别胡说了
Nuts to that.
- 嘿 他有没有跟你说起过史密蒂？
- 艾文...
- Hey, did you tell him about Smitty?
- Irving...
史密蒂？
Smitty?
- 亨尼西先生...
- 艾文...
- Mr. Hennessy...
- Irving...
等到...
Wait till...
你又来了 艾文
There you go again, Irving.
乔
Joe.
- 好吧 有什么话待会儿再说
- 听着...
- All right, save that till later.
- Listen...
不管怎样 你来早了点儿 你干嘛不先回家去刮个胡子呢？
You're here early, anyway. Why don't you go home and shave?
刮胡子？
Shave?
是的 要不就在我同亨尼西先生谈完之前保持安静
Yeah, or else keep quiet till Mr. Hennessy and I are finished talking.
嘿 这到底是怎么回事？
Hey, what kind of a routine is that?
你们两个在说什么？谁是史密蒂？
What are you two guys up to? Who's Smitty?
他是我们认识的一个人 你没必要在意他
He's a guy that we met. You wouldn't care for him.
要是我想看看呢？
What am I supposed to look at?
不用了 只不过是些艾文的美女照 你不会喜欢的
No, just a couple of Irving's dames. You wouldn't like them.
也许你会喜欢的
Maybe you would.
别岔开话题 昨天你走进我办公室的时候...
Don't change the subject. When you came back into my office yesterday...
是的 我知道 昨天下午 我以为自己掌握了个好料
Yeah, I know, yesterday at noon, I thought I had a good lead,
可我弄错了
but I was wrong.
事情就是这样 什么料都没有
That's all there is to it. There is no story.
好吧
Okay.
她今天举行记者招待会 同样的时间 同样的地点
She's holding the press interview today. Same time, same place.
也许这次你能弄到料
Maybe that's one story you can get.
你还欠我500美元！
And you owe me 500 bucks!
从我的薪水里扣吧 每周50美元
Take it out of my salary, 50 bucks a week.
别以为我不会
Don't think I won't.
嘿 怎么了？
Hey, what gives?
有人给我们出更高的价吗？
Have we had a better offer?
艾文 我不知道该怎么跟你说 可是...
Irving, I don't know just how to tell you this, but...
我先坐下来再说吧
Wait till I sit down.
好了 关于这次的料还有这些照片
Well, in regard to the story that goes with these,
没有什么料
there is no story.
为什么没有？
Why not?
我是说 我之前没有考虑清楚
I mean, not as far as I'm concerned.
嘿 照片洗出来相当不错 你想看看吗？
Hey, the pictures came out pretty well. You want to have a look at them?
怎么样 从这么小的底片洗出来的？
How about a blowup from a negative that size?
- 这是她的第一支烟
- 噢 是啊 在Rocca咖啡馆
- That's her first cigarette.
- Oh, yeah. At Rocca's.
嘿 诚实之口
Hey, the mouth of truth.
噢 你想知道我给这张想的标题是什么吗？
Oh, you want to know the caption I had in mind there?
“闯入[公主生活]的理发师”
"Barber cuts in."
噢 这张我觉得应该排在最醒目的位置
Well, here's the one I figured would be the key shot for the layout.
“愿望成真之墙”
"The wall where wishes come true."
乔 这主意不错
Joe, that's good.
先是那些照片 然后就是愿望墙的照片
Lead off with that, then follow up with the wishes.
这是我从档案中找出来的
I dug that up out of the file.
“公主检阅警察”
"Princess inspects police."
耶
Yeah.
“警察检阅公主”
"Police inspects princess."
怎么样？
How about it?
- 乔 我有个好东西要给你
- 很好...
- Joe, I got a topper for you.
- Pretty good...
喔！
Wow!
- 这够冲击吧？
- 简直太棒了！
- Is that a shot?
- What a picture!
这够冲击吧 乔？
Is that a shot, Joe?
“保镖惨败”
"Bodyguard gets body blow."
耶 不 叫这个怎么样？
Yeah. No, how about this?
“加冕”
"Crowned head."
说得太对了！真是...乔 你说得...
I get it! That's... Joe, you got...
她就是供人评论的对象 乔
She's fair game, Joe.
对公主怎么报导都可以
It's always open season on princesses.
你一定是疯了
You must be out of your mind.
是的 我知道 不过...
Yeah, I know, but...
好了 听着 如果你打算卖掉这些照片的话我也阻止不了你
Well, look, I can't prevent you from selling the pictures if you want to.
- 你可以拿它们卖个好价钱
- 没错！
- You'll get a good price for them.
- Yeah!
你这是要去记者招待会吗？
You going to the interview?
你去吗？
Are you going?
是的 这是我的任务 不是吗？
Yeah. It's an assignment, isn't it?
是的
Yeah.
再见
I'll see you.
这儿虽然不怎么样 但这就是别人的家
It ain't much, but it's home.
女士们先生们 请都过来
Ladies and gentlemen, please approach.
公主殿下
Her Royal Highness.
公主殿下 这都是来自新闻界的女士及先生们
Your Royal Highness, the ladies and gentlemen of the press.
女士们先生们
Ladies and gentlemen,
公主殿下现在将回答你们的提问
Her Royal Highness will now answer your questions.
我想在一开始 公主殿下
I believe at the outset, Your Highness,
我应代表在场的各位
that I should express the pleasure of all of us
为您身体康复表示祝贺
at your recovery from the recent illness.
谢谢
Thank you.
公主殿下您相信建立联盟
Does Your Highness believe that federation would be
是解决欧洲经济问题的可行之道吗？
a possible solution to Europe's economic problems?
我支持任何
I am in favor of any measure
可以促进欧洲各国紧密合作的措施
which would lead to closer cooperation in Europe.
请问 在公主殿下您看来
And what, in the opinion of Your Highness,
各国未来的关系前景怎样？
is the outlook for friendship among nations?
我对此充满信心
I have every faith in it,
就如我对人与人之间的关系充满信心一样
as I have faith in relations between people.
请准许我代表我的通讯社发言
May I say, speaking for my own press service,
我们相信公主殿下的信念是不会被辜负的
we believe that Your Highness's faith will not be unjustified.
很高兴听到你这么说
I am so glad to hear you say it.
公主殿下您所造访过的城市里最喜欢那一座？
Which of the cities visited did Your Highness enjoy the most?
每座城市都有其...
Each in its own way...
每座城市都有其令人难忘之处
Each in its own way was unforgettable.
很难说是...
It would be difficult to...
罗马
Rome.
一定要说的话 罗马
By all means, Rome.
我会毕生珍藏出访这里的回忆
I will cherish my visit here in memory as long as I live.
即便在这里偶染微恙也是吗 公主殿下？
Despite your indisposition, Your Highness?
即便如此
Despite that.
现在可以拍照了
Photographs may now be taken.
谢谢 女士们先生们 非常感谢
Thank you, ladies and gentlemen. Thank you very much.
我很高兴能认识一些新闻界的女士还有先生们
I would now like to meet some of the ladies and gentlemen of the press.
希区柯克 芝加哥每日新闻报
Hitchcock, Chicago Daily News.
- 很高兴在这里认识你
- 谢谢
- I'm so happy to see you here.
- Thank you.
斯坎扎尼 瑞士报
Scanziani, de La Suisse.
克林格 德国通讯社
Klinger, Deutsche Presse-Agentur.
莫里斯 蒙塔布里 费加罗报
Maurice Montabre, Le Figaro.
赛特斯克 嘉乐玛 阿姆斯特丹线报
Sytske Galema, De Linie, Amsterdam.
雅克 法瑞尔 这里是巴黎杂志
Jacques Ferrier, Ici Paris.
格罗斯 达维 特拉维夫报
Gross, Davar, Tel Aviv.
科尔特斯 卡瓦尼尔斯 马德里ABC电视台
Cortes Cavanillas, ABC, Madrid.
兰普 纽约先驱论坛报
Lampe, New York Herald-Tribune.
- 下午好
- Good afternoon.
艾文 拉多维奇 CR图片社
Irving Radovich, CR Photo Service.
你好
How do you do?
请允许我向公主殿下赠送一些您此次罗马之行的纪念照片好吗？
May I present Your Highness with some commemorative photos of your visit to Rome?
真是非常感谢
Thank you so very much.
乔 布兰德利 美国通讯社
Joe Bradley, American News Service.
我真高兴 布兰德利先生
So happy, Mr. Bradley.
莫里昂斯 巴塞罗那先锋报
Moriones, La Vanguardia de Barcelona.
史蒂芬 豪斯 伦敦交易电讯报[译者没有WIKI到这家报纸]
Stephen House of The London Exchange Telegraph.
下午好
Good afternoon.
德 奥迪斯欧 法新社
De Aldisio, Agence Presse.